## SPENCER RINEHART

# 1505 Huckleberry Lane, Austin TX 78748 (757) 630-3572

## anubis@overthemonkey.com

I am a full-stack engineer with over ten years of PHP experience and over four years of Node.js experience. I have extensive experience with Linux as a development machine and as the base of a production software stack. Over the past five years, I have also worked on various DevOps projects gaining experience with Docker, Ansible, Puppet, Chef, Jenkins CI, and Amazon Web Services. I am passionate about establishing best practices for an engineering team including proper version control usage, open source software, continuous integration, **12-factor architecture**, and community development, including hackathons and coding competitions.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### FLOSPORTS-EVENTS

#### Software Engineer January 2016-Present

I am currently a software engineer for FloSports where I work on a live-streaming platform for sporting events. I am using my experience with PHP to build a scalable API for managing athlete and team identities, and an event registration system built on top of Angular 2.

#### HELP.COM-LIVE CHAT

#### Software Engineer September 2014-January 2016

I was a full-stack software engineer for Help.com where I helped build a live chat application. i I laid the foundation for a Docker-based production deployment system and built some of the core components of Help.com's microservice-based architecture. I worked extensively on building Node.js microservices and instrumenting them in our frontend Ampersand.js (a Backbone.js derivative) application.

#### DOMINION ENTERPRISES-TRADERONLINE.COM

#### Web Programmer June 2006-September 2014

I worked at Dominion Enterprises for 8 years on a variety of web applications, APIs, and DevOps/Systems applications. My primary role was a PHP software engineer with a focus on APIs and core functionality. I also led projects for release management and server/process automation. I was the head of a company-wide Open Source committee and a member of the company's Technical Talent Acquisition Group (TTAG).

Some of the key projects that I led include:

- introducing and managing version control systems including automated release processes;
- · introducing unit testing and test-driven development;
- · developing a RESTful API and converting applications to access it;
- · developing an AWS cloud-based automated deployment process utilizing continuous delivery; and
- establishing the company's open source portfolio, leading up a committee to maintain it, and evangelising OSS to the company as a whole.

The websites I serviced are primarily focused on classified advertising and dealer inventory and recieve thousands of requests per minute. I gained work-related experience with PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS/Less, Ruby, Puppet, Chef, Linux, MongoDB, SOLR, and

Python, among other technologies.

## # EDUCATION

## VIRGINIA TECH

## Computer Science August 2003-May 2006

In three years, I received a B.S. in Computer Science.

# **S**KILLS

#### PRIMARY EXPERTISE

- PHP 10+ years
- Node.js 4+ years
- Docker 3+ years
- Linux 10+ years

## ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- HTML/CSS/JS 10+ years
- AWS 3+ years
- Ansible/Chef/Puppet 3+ years
- Ruby 3 years